Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太と
ひびと
栄光の日 生まれの弟･日々人＞
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
＜日本人初の
ﾑｰﾝｳｫｰｶとなった日々人は➡
To treat the panic disorder that's afflicted him since a lunar accident, Hibito went to Russia.
月面での事故の影響による➡
パニック障害を克服するため
リハビリの日々を送る＞
But now, Mutta is finally one step closer to the moon.
＜一方 日々人のはるか後ろから
月を目指し始めた六太は➡
ついに新たな一歩を踏み出す＞
During NEEMO training, he will live in the environment closest to that of the moon,
ニーモ
＜NEEMO訓練 地球上で最も月面を
再現できる海底基地で➡
within a simulated lunar habitat.
シミュレーション生活を
するというもの＞
For this training, his life will be in real danger.
＜死の危険も伴う
油断できない訓練＞
In the coming days, Mutta and the other astronauts will face difficult trials.
＜六太たちに
重い試練がのしかかる＞
ど どいうことですか？
Wh-What do you mean?
(ラブ)言葉の通りだ
最初から決まっていた｡
That's how it is.
It was decided before we began.
お前ら２人のうち➡
Only one of you
月へ行けるのは
どちらか１人だけだ｡
can go to the moon.
そ そんな…｡
N-No way...
Swayed by a profound sadness
My daydreams lay a bouquet at my feet
space brothers
I stand atop a brand new world
Hoping to catch whatever falls out of this unprecedented miracle
They're here yet again
The days I'll spend growing distant from you
I'll have miles to go before I sleep in peace
I can see the faint radiance of hope
It got mixed into your blood one day and hasn't let you go
That's all
My body grows nimbler by the day
And my heart's shedding tears because it can't keep up
But I lost something once I became an adult
My light slumber
I can see the faint radiance of hope
It's mixed into your blood, so I'll never let you go
That's all
My body stands atop a stage that it won't run away from even if it rains
That makes me break out into a sprint, so goodbye
My midnight slumbers
#83 Kenji and I
Ooh, wow...
何度 見ても…美しい！
They're always so beautiful to behold!
なんば
(南波六太)《俺とケンジ➡
It's between Kenji and me...
どちらか１人だけしか…
月へは行けない》
Only one of us can go to the moon?
《何でだよ…
何でそんなことになるんだ！》
Why?!
Why does it have to be this way?
《チクショー！》
Damn!
《何で俺とケンジなんだ！》
Why did they pair Kenji and me?!
それは本当のことですか？
ラブさん｡➡
Is that really true, Love?
くつがえることがない
決定事項ですか？
Is there no way to circumvent that decision?
そうだ…
お前らだけじゃなく➡
No.
It isn't just you.
The same rule applies to the other Ants.
他のチームの｢アンツ｣も同じだ｡
俺が 何でお前らに
これを伝えたか➡
You should think carefully about why I've told you the truth.
よ～く考えて これからを過ごせ｡
Thinking about it won't change anything...
《そんなこと…
考えても仕方ねぇよ》
《ケンジは俺より ずっと前から
月の訓練を始めてるんだ》
Kenji began to train for the moon long before I did.
《比べるまでもなく➡
They don't need to bother comparing us.
ケンジだろ 選ばれるのは》
Kenji will be chosen.
《俺は 何で
ここに呼ばれたんだ！》
Why did they even bring me here?
ムッ君 じっとしてても
意味がない｡
Mu...
Standing around is pointless.
とにかく作業を続けよう｡
Let's get back to work.
Y-Yeah...
Welcome back, Mutta! I've been waiting for you!
お帰り！ムッタ 待ってたよ～｡
見えたかい？
ウミガメが泳いでたよね｡
Did you see that? Sea turtles were swimming around...
あの美しく優雅な舞い…｡
They dance with such grace!
洗練された姿には
ホント心奪われるよね～！
Their measured movement always entrances me.
あ…そうなんだ
見逃しちゃったよ｡
Oh, that's nice...
Guess I missed them.
あ～そうかぁ～残念｡
Oh, really? That's too bad.
They were swimming nearby...
すぐ近くを
泳いでたはずなんだけどな～｡
でも きっと
また来てくれるよ｡
But I'm sure they'll be back.
そう落ち込まないで
ムッタ｡
Don't let it get you down, Mutta.
やぁ～ケンジ！
ウミガメ見えたかい？
Hey, Kenji!
Did you see the sea turtles? They were so cute!
かわいかったね～｡
いや 見なかったよ いたの？
No, I didn't see them. Were they nearby?
そうかぁ～残念だぁ～｡➡
Oh, that's too bad!
次 見た時は
マイクでちゃんと知らせるよ｡
Next time, I'll use the mic to notify you guys.
(ケンジ)ありがとう 大丈夫だよ｡
Thanks, I'm good.
うらや
僕は彼らが羨ましいよ～｡➡
I envy them so much...
肺呼吸なのに １時間くらい
海中にいられるからね～｡
They breathe using lungs, but they can stay submerged for an hour.
ウミガメが産卵の時に➡
Most people know that when sea turtles lay eggs, they cry...
涙を流すってのは
有名な話だよね？➡
実は あれは苦しくて
泣いてるわけじゃなくて➡
Well, they don't cry because they're in pain.
目の渇きを防ぐのと➡
They do it to get rid of excess salt and keep their eyes from drying out.
余分な塩分を排出するための
働きなんだよね～｡➡
でも まあ そうと分かってても➡
But even knowing that,
the first time I witnessed it, I found myself tearing up!
初めてあれを見た時は
僕も泣いたよねぇ～｡
アゥ…｡
《俺には やることがあるんだ！》
I have a task I need to complete...
《シャロンとの約束…》
I must keep my promise to Sharon.
⦅シャロン！⦆
Sharon!
⦅３年先か４年先か
分かんないけど 俺の中じゃ…⦆
It'll probably take three or four years before this will happen.
⦅俺が誰より先に選ばれて➡
But I plan to be the first one chosen to go to the moon and build your telescope.
月で望遠鏡を建てる予定だよ⦆
《シャロンの事情を知れば
ケンジも…》
If Kenji knew Sharon's condition, he would...
《そんなこと…
伝えてどうすんだ！》
What good would telling him about Sharon do?
How stupid am I?!
《バカか 俺は！》
《それを伝えて➡
Do I tell him about Sharon, and ask him to let me go to the moon this time?
｢今回の月は俺に譲ってくれ｣
とでも言うつもりか!?➡
｢俺が選ばれるように
ケンジは手を抜け｣とか➡
Ask him to underperform, so I'm chosen?
そんな信号を
あいつに送る気か!?》
Is that the message I want to send?
《くだらねぇ事 考えてんじゃねぇ
チクショー！》
Why am I even having these stupid ideas?!
はくじょう
《薄情者…だな》
I really am a heartless person...
《僕は こんなにも
薄情者だったのか…》
Am I really such a cruel person?
《いや でも
こうするしかないんだ｡➡
Even so, I have no choice...
僕らは 仲良く同じ方向を
向き過ぎていた》
For a long time, we've been working together, toward the same goal.
I don't think we've ever had a disagreement.
《互いの意見に対しても
しっかりとした議論もせず➡
すべて肯定し合ってた｡➡
We've always been united!
どちらか１人しか月へ行けないと
分かった以上➡
But if only one of us can go the moon,
二人三脚をしてちゃ
ダメなんだ！》
this isn't a three-legged race anymore!
《僕らは 縄を
ほどかなきゃならない》
We are no longer on the same side.
After working outside, I noticed something.
一度 外で作業してみて
思ったんだけど➡
資材を
ここまで持ってくるだけで➡
It'll take a considerable amount of time to move the materials here.
かなり時間がかかる｡
だから ムッ君
もう一度よく考えて話し合おう｡
So, Mu...
We should do another review.
今回の月面基地周辺設備に➡
To decide what's really essential for our Moonbase design.
必要な物と そうでない物を｡
O-Okay...
これが 今 出てる案の
設計図だよ｡
Here's our current proposed design.
僕は 前に言ってた
大容量の通信アンテナは➡
I'm considering leaving out that high-capacity antenna I mentioned.
今回 省こうと思ってる｡
もっと時間に
余裕を持たせよう｡➡
We can put the time to use elsewhere.
ムッ君の言ってた充電ポストは
必要だと思う｡➡
Your charging stations are important.
人命に関わるものだからね｡
Because they can save lives.
だけど
悪いんだけど ムッ君｡
But I'm sorry, Mu.
月面望遠鏡は
今回は なくていいと思う｡
I don't think the lunar telescope will be necessary this time.
《唐突に にごり出した
ケンジとの空気感に…》
The sudden change in Kenji's attitude...
Hey, hey! Look at this!
お前の意見は？ムッタ｡
What do you think, Mutta?
お 俺は…｡
Uh, I...
《｢早く この訓練
終わってくれよ｣と➡
...made me wish the training would just end.
逃げ出したい気持ちに
なっていた…》
So that I could run away.
To ensure we have enough time to build our base,
この基地製作
余裕を持って作業するために➡
大容量通信アンテナを
やめようと思う｡
I believe we should give up the high-capacity communication antenna.
ただ そうすると
望遠鏡の膨大なデータなんかは➡
But that means it won't be possible to send large amounts of data from the telescope to Earth in real time.
リアルタイムで地上に送れない
ということになる｡
だから ムッ君｡➡
So, Mu...
大容量通信アンテナを
作らない以上は➡
If we aren't adding the high-capacity antenna,
月面望遠鏡の設置も
やめた方がいいと思うんだ｡
I think we should postpone the telescope, as well.
Wow!
ワーオ！
確かに…｡
That makes sense.
ねぇねぇ みんな
見てごらんよ！
Hey, guys... Look over here!
お前の意見は？
ムッタ｡
What do you think, Mutta?
お 俺は…｡
Uh, I...
If that's what Kenji thinks,
ケンジがそう言うなら➡
諦めるしか…ないかな｡
I guess I can give up the telescope...
フン｡
じゃあ 基地に追加する設備は➡
In that case, the additional facilities will be mega solar panels, a secondary debris barrier,
メガソーラーパネルと
二次デブリ防護壁｡➡
そして充電ポスト
…という事で ＯＫかな？➡
and charging stations.
Is everyone okay with that?
どう？ラブさん｡
What do you think, Love?
(ラブの声)ああ それくらいなら
出来るだろう｡
Yeah, that sounds feasible.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)デーモン ジム
各チームの様子は？
Damon, Jim...
How are the teams doing?
スリー
(ﾃﾞｰﾓﾝ)チームⅢに続いて
チームⅡもだ｡
In addition to Team 3, Team 2 also knows the truth.
ガゼボ内で事実を告げたと
ラブから知らせがあった｡
Love said that they were taken to the gazebo for the disclosure.
そうか…｡
I see...
チームⅡのアンツは とりわけ
仲のいい２人だったけど➡
The Team 2 Ants were close, but ever since then,
急に会話が少なくなったよ｡
they've barely spoken.
I'm sure they have a lot to think about...
今は２人とも
いろいろ考えてんだろうな｡
自分が選ばれるために
何をどうすればいいのか｡
They're wondering what they have to do to be chosen.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)わかった｡引き続き
訓練を進めてくれ｡➡
Understood.
Please continue with the training.
それから 交代要員を含め 管制の
監視員全員に伝えといてくれ｡
Also, I have a message for all staff members on call, including the control room observers...
｢アンツ｣の目立った言動は
全て逐一 私に報告するように｡
If any of the Ants say something of note,
report it to me immediately.
マカベケンジ 潜水開始！
Makabe Kenji is beginning his dive!
何だか元気ないねぇ ムッタ｡
お腹でも痛いのかい？
You don't look so good, Mutta...
Do you have a stomachache?
胃薬あるよ 海草入り｡
ありがとう ハミルトン｡
I have some medicine made from seaweed.
Thanks, Hamilton.
大丈夫だよ｡
僕に出来ることなら
何でも言ってよね｡
I'm fine.
If there's anything I can do, let me know.
僕は君たちの
技術支援役なんだから｡
I'm here to provide support.
Yeah.
実は さっきまたウミガメを
見たんだよ｡
I just saw the sea turtles again!
まだ この辺りを泳いでるかも
しれないねぇ｡➡
They may still be around.
君たちにもぜひ
見てもらいたいんだよね～｡
I really want to show you how they look!
そんなにいいの？
ウミガメって｡
Are sea turtles that big a deal?
ハワイではねぇ
ウミガメを見ると➡
In Hawaii, there's a belief that seeing sea turtles predicts good fortune.
幸福がもたらされるという
言い伝えがあるんだよ｡
ここはフロリダだけど
海は繋がってるんだ｡
We're in Florida, but all the oceans are connected.
見るときっと
いい事があると思うんだよねぇ｡
If we see one, I'm sure something good will happen...
そうか なるほど～｡
じゃ 見ないとね｡
Oh, I understand...
Guess I should find one.
《幸福か…》
Good fortune...
《一番の幸福は
俺もケンジも月へ行ける事だ》
The best thing that could happen would be Kenji and me going to the moon together.
《そうなるものと
思ってたのに…》
I never imagined that it wouldn't be an option...
今日はもう この資材置き場には
戻ってこない｡
Today, we won't return to the staging area.
カートに積めるだけ積んどけ｡
了解！
Load as much on the cart as you can.
Roger that.
(ラブ)今日の月面基地製作は
１６時半までだ｡➡
Moonbase construction will continue until 16:30 today.
１７時からは 海中ローバーの
遠隔操作訓練が別にある｡
At 17:00, we'll start training to control the rovers remotely underwater.
ハァ～…｡
アンディ｡
Andy...
もう補給に来たのか｡
まだあるだろ？酸素｡
You came to resupply?
You should still have plenty of oxygen.
ま まあ…｡
Y-Yeah...
なんか ケンジとここで
一緒になったら気まずいからね｡
I thought if I ran into Kenji here, it might be awkward.
ちょっと早めに来た｡
そういうアンディこそ…｡
So I came a little early.
What about you, Andy?
I'm big, so I use up oxygen faster.
俺はデカイから
酸素の減りも早いんだ｡
Hey, Andy...
なあ アンディ…｡
俺かケンジのどっちかしか
月へ行けないってのは➡
When they say that only one of us can go to the moon...
この先ずっとの話なの？
Does it mean that the other can't ever go?
分かんねぇんだよ全く…｡
I don't understand it.
今回 選ばれなくても
何年後かには➡
If we aren't chosen this time, will we have the chance to go in a few years or not?
月へ行くチャンスがあるのか
ないのか…｡
Beats me.
さあな
そこまでは俺も知らん｡
I'm not in the loop.
というより…➡
And frankly,
上が いつ誰を何のﾐｯｼｮﾝに
アサインするか➡
no one can say who the bigwigs will assign to missions, or when.
なんてことは
誰にも分からんことだ｡
俺は去年のＩＳＳミッションが
初のフライトだったわけだが…➡
My first flight was last year, on an ISS mission.
I had to wait a long time.
ずいぶん待たされた｡➡
同期の奴らが
どんどん先に選ばれる中➡
All of my colleagues were being selected.
なぜ俺だけ選ばれないのか考え
苦しんだ時期もある…｡
I couldn't help but wonder why I hadn't been chosen...
｢なぜ俺はアサインされないのか｣
｢他の奴と何が違う｣➡
Why aren't they assigning me to a mission?
What makes the others better than me?
｢何を直せばいい｣➡
What do I have to fix?
｢デカイことに
何か問題があるのか｣➡
Is it because I'm so big?
Then why did they make me an astronaut?
｢じゃあ そもそもなぜ
俺は宇宙飛行士になれたんだ｣｡
俺はなんで
今ここにいるのか…｡
Right now, why am I here?
正直 教官の前で
ペンを落としただけでも➡
Back then, when I dropped a pen,
注意力が散漫な奴だと思われ
減点評価されるんじゃないかと➡
I ended up stressing about whether I would lose points for not paying attention.
ビクつくことさえあった｡
それで…
アンディはどうしたの？
So what did you do?
考えるのをやめたさ｡
I stopped thinking about it.
目の前にある訓練や仕事を
さらに増やして➡
I increased my training and workload,
それで
頭いっぱいにしてやった｡➡
to avoid having time to think of anything else.
そういう意味では
このＮＥＥＭＯ訓練は➡
As a result, this NEEMO training doesn't feel hard enough to me.
俺には ちと物足りんな｡
俺が本気のときは
もっとガンガン働けるぜ｡
When I'm serious,
I work much harder, Mutta.
ムッタよ｡
そろそろ酸素の補給に
行ってきます｡
I need to refill my oxygen tank.
ムッタ｡ジョイントパーツを
取って来てくれ｡
Mutta, bring me the joint parts.
Right.
はい｡
《｢考えるのをやめた｣か…》
He stopped thinking about it...
支援ダイバーから連絡があった｡
I just received a transmission from the support divers.
今 そちらの資材置き場の方に➡
There's a battery of barracudas heading toward your staging area.
バラクーダの群れが
接近しているそうなんだ｡
バラクーダ？
バラクーダってあの!?
Barracudas?
You mean those...
問題ないと思うけど➡
There shouldn't be a problem, but try not to scare them.
あまり刺激しないようにだけ
気をつけて｡
群れで泳ぐバラクーダは
神々しいから➡
The sight of barracudas swimming together is divine, so I hope I get to see them!
見てほしいんだよね～｡
Sounds like they're coming toward you, Mutta.
ムッタの方に向かってるぞ｡
Eh?
Wow...
うお おおお…うおぉ!?
ぐっ ぐうぅ…！
(ｱﾝﾃﾞｨ)大丈夫か？ムッタ｡
Are you okay, Mutta?
えっ ああ…何ともない｡
Y-Yeah, I'm fine...
《私の中にあった余分な気持ちを
洗い流してもらえたような➡
It was as if they'd swept all the feelings I didn't need from my body.
そんな出来事だった…》
That's how it felt...
みんな 今朝の俺の発言｡➡
Guys, I'd like to retract
諦めると言ったこと
取り消したい｡
what I said this morning about giving up.
俺ら宇宙飛行士は
宇宙へ行けるかわりに➡
We astronauts
go to space to fulfill the dreams of others.
誰かの願いに応えないと｡
科学とか 医学とか天文学とか➡
Scientists, doctors, astronomers...
学者たちの手足になることも
大事な仕事だよな｡
Our job is to become their hands and feet.
俺は
ホントは必要だと思ってる➡
I believe the high-capacity communication antenna and the lunar telescope are both necessary.
大容量通信アンテナも
月面望遠鏡も｡
時間内でどこまで作れるのか
みんなで あがいてみませんか｡
Let's all do what we can to complete them on time.
The hasty hare and the slow and steady turtle
Are both headed toward the place they call their goals
We forgot something very important once we grew up
Forget tomorrow, what can I do right now?
But the two of us
Have always remembered
The importance of taking off
The heavy shackles of hesitation
A brand new world
Is always waiting one step ahead of us
Even our failures will give us strength
And that will be the start of a new world
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#84 Supandaman
If we keep at it, I'm sure we'll find a way!
＜あがけば きっと
やれることはあるはずだ＞
But what, exactly, should we do?
＜でも
一体 どうすればいいんだ＞
I'm sorry, Mu, but I plan to go to the moon.
(ケンジ)＜ムッ君には悪いけど
僕は 月へ行く｡➡
My family gives me strength!
家族の思いの分 僕は強い＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Supandaman"